(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T09:41:43.348986",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
何をしても不器用で
No matter what I do, I'm clumsy,
何かとミスしてばっか
And I just keep making mistakes.
駄目駄目な私だってできることがあるの
Even a good-for-nothing like me can do great things!
凹んで悲しくたって笑顔にしてあげるんだ
Even if you're depressed and sad, I'll make you smile!
ここにいるから早く私を見つけてね
I'm right here, so find me quickly, okay?
愛しくても いつまでも隣にいるし
No matter what, I'll always be by your side,
いつでも一緒に笑える私をたくさん知って
And know that I'll always be smiling right beside you.
たくさん好きって言って わがままであさもにがて
Say you love me lots—I'm selfish and bad with mornings,
飛び出しちゃ駄目駄目だけど それでも私のことを見ててね
I mustn't run off, but even so, please keep watching me!
描く夢の未来へ続く
Continuing toward the future of the dreams we draw...
道を 君と歩けますように
May I walk down this path with you,
でももっと 好きになってもらいたいな
but I want you to love me even more!
頭の中は 君ばかりで 床が抜けたって 気づいてないで
My head is full of you, so don't even notice if the floor breaks!
あぁ もう やきもちしちゃうわ
Ah, I'm already getting jealous.
あぁ ずっと 好きがいいの
Ah, I want you to love me forever,
心の奥も 染めちゃうくらいに こっち向いててよね ダーリン
enough to dye my heart too, so look this way, darling!
あぁ もう 離さないから 絶対に
Ah, I won't let go anymore, definitely!
愛して もっと 君がいるから私
Love me more, because you're here,
いつでも 頑張れるんだ
I can always do my best!
今日は3周年 スパッとライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my 3rd anniversary live!
あくあ色に染まれ！
Get dyed in Aqua color!
君がいるから 歩いてこれた
Because you're here, I was able to walk this far,
君がいなくちゃ 前も見れない
and without you, I can't even see ahead.
いやなこととか つらいこととかあったって
Even when bad or painful things happened,
君の力で ここまで笑ってこれたんだ
thanks to your strength, I could laugh and get this far.
君がいるから 私がいるの
Because you're here, I exist.
こんな私を 愛してくれない？ ねぇもっと
Won't you love this kind of me? Hey, even more,
ねぇもっと まだもっと 受け止めてよね
still more, accept me, okay?
ねえ さあ 声を上げて
Hey, now raise your voice!
でももっと 好きになってもらいたいな
But I want you to love me even more!
いつでもそう 私は神みたいに そっぽなんて向いてないわ
I'm not always looking away like a god!
ねえほら 夢中にしちゃうわ
Hey look, I'll make you obsessed with me.
あぁ ずっと こっち向いててよね ダーリン
Ah, keep looking this way, darling!
あぁ もう 離さないから 絶対に
Ah, I won't let go anymore, definitely!
絶対よ 約束だよ
Definitely, it's a promise!
愛しちゃう もっと！
I'll love you even more!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me,
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聴かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all!
あれほどやめてって言った タバコもお酒も
I told you so much to stop smoking and drinking,
肝臓やられて お釈迦になっても看護してあげないんだから
even if your liver gets ruined, I won't nurse you!
あーいうこと言うことでも聞かない
You talk back to everything, yet won't listen.
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black!
言いたいことは言わないし
You won't say what you want to say,
おねがいダーリン 見て聴いて 欲しいのは形の無いもの
Please, darling, look and listen, what I want is something shapeless.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聴いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方 真っ直ぐ見つめて
I won't make fun of you. Look, listen, peek deep into my eyes, gaze straight ahead!
おねだりしてみて欲しいの ダーリン
I want you to pester me, darling!
ダーリン 私あなたの気持ち全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all!
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷりって
I gazed at you so devotedly, yet now you're completely pretending not to know.
連れないときは連れないし
When you're cold, you're cold,
ねえなんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない
Hey, isn't that just stupid?
どこか足元見てる感じで
Feeling like you're appraising me from below!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to pester me,
ダーリン あなたは私の言うこと全然聞かない
Darling, you don't listen to what I say at all.
あれほどやめてって言った煙草もお酒も
I've told you so much to stop smoking and drinking,
毎日二箱七缶一日たりとも欠かさず
Two packs and seven cans every single day without fail.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver's ruined and you're done for,
看病してあげないんだから
I won't nurse you back to health!
ああ言えばこう言う てこでもきかない
You have a comeback for everything and won't budge an inch,
あなたのハートは真っ黒です
Your heart is pitch black.
言葉にできない臆病さは
The cowardice you can't put into words
下らないことではないのよ
Isn't just some trivial thing.
甘えてないで口に出してよ
Don't just act spoiled, say it out loud.
もうちゃんとこっち向いてったら
Just properly turn this way already!
おねだりダーリン見て聞いて 欲しいのは形のないもの
Please, darling, look and listen, what I want is a shapeless thing.
馬鹿にしないでよ見て聞いて 怒らないでよ瞳の奥の方
Don't make fun of me, look and listen, don't get mad, deep in my eyes.
おねだりダーリン寝てないで暴いてよ私の素顔を
Please, darling, don't sleep, expose my true face.
おねだりダーリン側にいて触らせて心の奥の方
Please, darling, stay by my side, let me touch deep in your heart.
真っ直ぐ見つめておねだりしてみてほしいの
Gaze straight ahead and pester me.
ダーリン私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
Darling, I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに今ではすっかり知らんぷり
I gazed at you so devotedly, yet now you completely play dumb.
っていうかそれって胡坐かいてるだけなんじゃないんですか
I mean, aren't you just resting on your laurels?
おねだりダーリン
Onegai Darling
改めまして、こんにちは！
Hello again, everyone!
みなさんこんにちはです！
Hello everyone!
みなさん元気ー？
How is everyone doing?
といい……
And, uh...
水を……
Water...
ということで、今の話、あの「素直な人」にしか見えない水でございます。
So, the water I just mentioned is water only "honest people" can see.
みんなにはきっと見えたと思うんだけど、
I'm sure you all definitely saw it, right?
はい、ということでついに始まりました！
Yes, so it has finally begun!
みなとあか、3Dライブ、あかいろ……3周年ライブということで3周年でーす！
Minato Aqua's 3D Live, Akairo... 3rd Anniversary Live! It's our 3rd anniversary!
ということでね、えーま8月の8日に、
So, uh, on August 8th,
え私みなとあか3周年を迎えました！
I, Minato Aqua, celebrated my 3rd anniversary!
ありがとうー！
Thank you so much!
ま、当日のね、え、昨日の8月8日は、えーまね、あの、今日こうしてね、あの、このライブばーって、すごいライブをするためにね、
As for yesterday on August 8th, well, to put on this amazing live show today,
ま、ちょっと、あの準備を準備を準備をしてね、ま次の日の9日に、えライブをさせていただくってことになったんだけれども、
we prepared and prepared so we could hold the live on the 9th the next day, but...
え、今日はね、えま、5月に続いて、3Dライブを開催しても2回目のね、えYouTube無料3Dライブなんだけれども、
And today, following May, this is our second free YouTube 3D live,
え、まダンスレッスンしたり、えーまいろんなね準備とかをね進めてきました！みんな、ワクワクしてますかー？
and we've done dance lessons and various preparations! Are you all excited?
ワクワクしてますかー？
Are you excited?
私さ、もうね、やばいよ、
You know, for me, it's crazy,
ワクワクがとまんないよ！
my excitement just won't stop!
なんかね、もうね、みんなね、もうこの1年いろんなことがあって、もうなんかおかげさまで、配信以外でもね、いろんな活動をさせていただいておりまして、
Over this past year, so many things have happened, and thanks to you all, I've been able to do various activities outside of streaming as well.
いや本当にね応援してくださってありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for always supporting me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
まね、そんな日頃の感謝を込めて、今日は短い時間ではありますが、え、アイドル銀河一アイドルのみなとあかをお届けするので、
So, putting that daily gratitude into words, today, though it's a short time, I'll be delivering Minato Aqua, the number one idol in the galaxy,
え、みんな最後までついてきてくれると嬉しいでーす！
so I'd be so happy if you all follow along until the very end!
ちなみになね、えっとね、ちょっと俺のここ5月と何か同じじゃないって思った人いるかもしれないけど、
By the way, some of you might be thinking, "Hey, isn't this the same as May?"
ちょっと待ってねって！ちゃんとね、えっと、今日のためにいろんなもの準備してるので、お楽しみにしていただけたら嬉しいなって思ってます！
But wait a minute! I'm properly preparing various things just for today, so I hope you're looking forward to it!
そして、え、このライブの後、え前回の5月にやってすごい好評だった、えーメンバーシップ限定の、えーと生放送が、えーあります！なのでね、え、メンバーの方はライブが終わったら、え見てくれると嬉しいです！
And, after this live, we have the membership-only live broadcast that was super popular when we did it last May! So members, I'd be happy if you check it out after the live!
メンバーじゃないって人はね、あのこの機関にぜひね、今がね、あののみなとあかのメンバーシップにこっちかな？こっちかな？メンバーシップになって、えー一緒にね、え3Dのメインゲンライブ見てくれたら嬉しいです！
For those who aren't members, please take this opportunity to become a member of Minato Aqua's channel and watch the 3D main-gen live together with us!
それじゃあ次、えー私がね、え初めての歌ってみた動画で歌ったあの曲、聴いて――
Now then, next, that song I sang in my very first cover video, listen to...
聞いてください！ インドア系ならトラックメイカー！
Listen up! If you're an indoor type, it's Track Maker!
マイハウスは段ボール
My house is cardboard boxes,
NEWハウス エレクトロハウス
New house, electro house.
トラックドライバー 通勤ラッシュ
Truck driver, commuter rush.
アップなロードはテンションMAX
Upward load with max tension!
ハウスダスト ノンフィクション
House dust, non-fiction.
花粉症には マスクメロン
For hay fever, a mask melon.
カーソル待ってよ クラクション
Wait for the cursor, car horn.
ほらクリック リリック トラックメイカー
Look, click, lyric, track maker!
お洒落の極地だ ファッションセンター
The peak of style, Fashion Center!
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, put your hands up!
ジャージにワイシャツ 絶対ヘンだ
Jersey and a dress shirt is totally weird!
MIDI トラックメイカー
MIDI track maker!
お洒落の聖地だ ファッションセンター
The sanctuary of style, Fashion Center!
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, put your hands up!
納期は明日だ 絶対徹夜
The deadline is tomorrow, absolute all-nighter!
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, track maker!
ロリ顔コンプなつるぺたっぴ
A flat-chested loli-faced complex,
ホップで ステップ ダブルステップ
Hop, step, double step!
フロアのあいつは ロボットダンス
That guy on the floor is doing robot dance.
お酒も入って そこスキンナイス
With some drinks in, it's pretty nice.
ネクタイ緩めた 今こそチャンス
Loosening the tie, now's the chance!
黒ぶちメガネに 細身のパンツ
Black-rimmed glasses and slim pants,
ふたりを揺るがす ワーブベース
A warp bass shaking the two of us.
今夜も残念 玉砕です
Tonight is also a regretful crushing defeat.
お洒落の極地だ ファッションセンター
The peak of style, Fashion Center!
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, put your hands up!
ジャージにジャージは アウトドア派
Jersey on jersey is the outdoor style!
インドア系なら トラックメイカー
If you're an indoor type, it's track maker!
お洒落の聖地だ ファッションセンター
The sanctuary of style, Fashion Center!
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, put your hands up!
ピークを抑えろ マキシマイザー
Suppress the peak, maximizer!
眠気のピークに カフェイン投下
Dropping caffeine at the peak of sleepiness!
お洒落の極地だ ファッションセンター
The peak of style, Fashion Center!
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, put your hands up!
ジャージにワイシャツ 絶対ヘンだ
Jersey and a dress shirt is totally weird!
MIDI トラックメイカー
MIDI track maker!
お洒落の聖地だ ファッションセンター
The sanctuary of style, Fashion Center!
両手を掲げて クラッピョヘンザ
Raise both hands, put your hands up!
納期は明日だ 絶対徹夜
The deadline is tomorrow, absolute all-nighter!
エビデイ エビナイ トラックメイカー
Everyday, every night, track maker!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
ファッションセンター
Fashion Center!
クラップ ヘンザ
Clap henza!
曖昧なボリュームじゃまだ足りない
Ambiguous volume is still not enough!
dB上げて 世界は透明だ
Raise the dB, the world is transparent!
境界線はもうどこにもない 感情の振動をまんま伝えるよ
Boundaries are nowhere to be found, I'll convey emotional vibrations directly!
応えてよ！
Answer me!
七色仕様エモーショングラフィックス
Rainbow-spec emotion graphics!
君に届いているかな？
Are they reaching you?
もっと聴かせてよ！
Let me hear more!
波状的信号コミュニケーション ねぇ君が見つけてみて
Wave-signal communication, hey, try and find me!
歌声の中の真実なところ 鳴らせHi-Fiな想いと
The truth inside the singing voice, ring out with Hi-Fi feelings!
次元を超え胸打つメロディー そして現実的な秘密教えよう
A melody that crosses dimensions and strikes your heart, and let's tell a realistic secret!
《この歌は永遠に生きていく》 だから“会いたい”なんてナンセンス
"This song lives forever," so saying "I miss you" is nonsense!
ユビキタスするよ君のメモリーに ほら君が私を呼ぶのなら 耳すまして
I'll be ubiquitous in your memory, hey, if you're calling me, listen closely!
曖昧なボリューム じゃ まだ 足りない
Ambiguous volume is still not enough,
なあ dB ( デシベル ) 上げて
Raise that dB!
世界 は 透明 だ
The world is transparent,
境界線 は もう どこ に も ない
boundaries are nowhere to be found.
感情 の 振動 を まんま 伝える よ 応え て よ !
I'll convey every single emotional vibration, so answer me!
七色 仕様 エモーション グラフィー
Seven-color custom emotionography,
君 に 届い て いる か な ? もっと 聴か せ て よ !
is it reaching you? Let me hear more!
波状 的 信号 コミュニケート
Wavetable signal communication,
ねえ 君 が 見つけ て み て
hey, try finding it yourself.
歌声 ( こえ ) の 中 の 真実 ( ピュア ) な とこ
Exorcise the pure truth within the voice,
鳴らせ hi - fi な 想い と 次元 を 越え 胸 打つ メロディー
and let that hi-fi melody ring out across dimensions!
そして 現実的 ( リアール ) な 秘密 教えよ う
And I'll teach you a realistic secret.
《 この 歌 は 永遠 ( とわ ) に 生き て いく よ 》
"This song will live on forever."
だから “ 会い たい ” なんて ナンスエンス
That's why saying "I want to see you" is nonsense.
ユミキタ する よ 君 の メモリー に
I'll be ubiquitous in your memory.
ほら 君 が 私 を 呼ぶ の なら 耳 澄まし て
Hey, if you're calling me, tune your ears in.
繊細 に ゲージ 増減 し たら dB ( デシベル ) 下げ て
With the fine-tuned gauge adjustments, lower the dB!
“ 一人きり だ ” なんて 壁 は もう 通用 し ない
"I'm all alone" is no longer an excuse.
一緒 に 揺れよ それ が 歌 だ から 託し て よ !
Sway with me, because this is a song—just trust it!
共鳴 機能 エモーション レスキュー
Resonance function emotion rescue,
君 に ちゃんと 見える か な ?
can you see me clearly?
もっと 手 を 振っ て !
Wave your hands more!
感情 的 干渉 は ダイレクト
Emotional interference is direct,
見つけ た ! 点滅 し てる
I found it! It's flashing—
それ が 君 の
that's your true self.
響け アッパー な リズム で
Resonate with an upbeat rhythm,
強制 的 上げ て く ハート ビート
forcibly raising your heartbeat.
ごめん でも ぜひ 聴い て ほしい ん だ
I'm sorry, but I really want you to listen—
君 の ため だけ に 歌う から
I'm singing this just for you.
なぜか ちょっと 泣け ちゃっ て
For some reason I feel like crying a little,
君 が 笑っ て くれ た せい だけ ど
all because you smiled at me.
そっ か 通り合える あたたかさ は 初めて か な
Is this our first time truly connecting?
ここ は どこ でしょ 私 は 誰 でしょ
Where is this? Who am I?
声 を 頼り に 探し て よ
Find me by relying on my voice.
心 で 歌う よ 心 に 届い て ほしい よ
I'll sing with my heart, I want it to reach your heart.
夢 も リアル も 本当 だ よ
Both dreams and reality are true.
鳴らせ hi - fi な 想い と 次元 を 越え 胸 打つ メロディー
Ring out, hi-fi feelings, a melody that crosses dimensions,
そして 現実的 ( リアール ) な 秘密 教えよ う
and let me teach you a realistic secret.
だから “ 会い たい ” なんて ナンスエンス
That's why saying "I want to see you" is nonsense.
ユミキタ する よ 君 の メモリー に
I'll be ubiquitous in your memory.
ほら 君 が 私 を 呼ぶ の なら 耳 澄まし て
Hey, if you're calling me, tune your ears in.
いつも そば に いる よ dB ( デシベル ) を 上げ て
I'll always be by your side, turn up the dB!
One two
エマージェンシー 零時 奴ら は クレイジー ・ イン ・ ザ ・ タウン
Emergency at midnight, they're going crazy in town,
家 に 籠っ て
huddled up at home,
ゴロゴロ ゴロゴロ と
rolling, rolling around.
堕落 の 夜 に 絡み付い た
Entangled in the falling night...
ルルル 放つ 言葉 は ルルル 腐っ てい た
Ruru, the words released were ruru, rotting away.
正論 も 常識 も 意味 を 持た ない 都会 に サヨナラ !
Saying goodbye to a metropolis where righteousness and common sense mean nothing!
引きこもり 絶対 ジャスティス 俺 の 私 だけ の 繭 の 中 で
Hikikomori absolute justice, inside my very own cocoon,
聴き殺し て ランデブー 俺 の 私 の 音 が キミ に 染まる まで
listening closely to the rendezvous, until my sound permeates you.
引きこもり 絶対 ジャスティス 俺 の 私 だけ の 繭 の 中 で
Hikikomori absolute justice, inside my very own cocoon,
聴き殺し て ランデブー 俺 の 私 の 音 を キミ が 包む だけ
listening closely to the rendezvous, until my sound wraps around you.
エマージェンシー 0時奴らは
Emergency at 0 o'clock, they're
クレイジー・イン・ザ・タウン
crazy in the town,
家に篭って ゴロゴロ ゴロゴロと
staying at home, rumbling, rumbling,
堕落の夜に 絡みついた
tangled on the night of fallen.
ルルル 放つ言葉は
(Lulu) The words let out are
ルルル 腐っていた
(Lulu) rotting away.
正論も常識も
Right and common sense
意味を持たない都市にサヨナラ
say goodbye to a meaningless city!
引き篭もり 絶対 ジャスティス
Staying inside, absolute justice,
俺の私だけの 折の中で
inside my, my own cage,
聴き殺してランデブー
listen to death, rendezvous.
俺の私の音が 君に染まるまで
Until my sound dyes into you,
引き篭もり 絶対 ジャスティス
staying inside, absolute justice,
俺の私だけの 折の中で
inside my, my own cage,
エマージェンシー 0時 流石に
Emergency at 0 o'clock, as expected
クレイジーな計画はお陀仏
the crazy plan is a goner,
グルグル グルグルと
rumbling, rumbling,
世界は変わらず廻っていた
the world kept spinning unchanged.
ルルル 君の視線が
(Lulu) Your gaze
ルルル ぼやけて尽きる
(Lulu) blurs away.
マリオネットな感情に 気付いてしまった
I realized my marionette-like emotions.
相も変わらずJamる街 止めぬNervousに
The town jams as always, don't get misled
惑わされないで
by endless nervous!
引き篭もり 絶対 ジャスティス
Staying inside, absolute justice,
俺の私だけの 折の中で
inside my, my own cage,
聴き殺してランデブー
listen to death, rendezvous.
俺の私の音が 君に染まるまで
Until my sound dyes into you,
Wowow 時がきた今
Wowow, now that the time has come,
Wowow エゴ放つのさ
Wowow, release your ego!
Wowow 家に篭って 狂い咲く
Wowow, staying at home, blooming wildly!
はーい、ということで！
Hii, so!
続いて3曲をお聴きいただきました！
You've just listened to 3 songs in a row!
まずは、インドア系ならトラックメーカー
First, for indoor-style, Track Maker.
こちらはね、もう3年前の2019年の2月の
This was, 3 years ago in February 2019,
バレンタインに歌ってみた動画を投稿していて
posted as a Valentine's cover video,
その後、指きりースベールは同じくこれも3年前？
and after that, Yubikiri Dezibel, also 3 years ago?
2019年の12月に投稿した曲です、ありがとう！
Posted in December 2019, thank you!
懐かしいね、本当に。
It's so nostalgic, really.
そして、今さっき披露したのが、もうつい最近、今年の4月に投稿した歌ってみた動画のグッバイ宣言でした！
And what I just performed earlier was "Goodbye Declaration", posted very recently in April of this year!
みんな見てくれて本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much everyone for watching!
いや動画もね、たくさん聴いてもらえててね、本当に嬉しかったです。
And you know, people listened to the video a lot, I was really happy.
ありがとうございます、ありがとね！
Thank you very much, thank you!
すごいね、マジでみんなね、聴いてくれてて、めっちゃよかったよ動画って言ってくれてて、すごくね、嬉しいです。
It's amazing, seriously everyone listened to it, and said the video was super good, I'm so happy.
ありがとう！でね、インドア系ならトラックメーカーをなんとですね、えっと、600万再生？
Thank you! And you know, Indoor-style Track Maker, amazingly, um, 6 million views?
なんか超えたらしい、最近。
It seems it crossed that recently.
すごいよね！信じられないんだけど。
That's amazing! I can't believe it.
だだだだ天使に次ぐ、いっしょまい再生がもうすぐ？もうすぐではないか。
Following "Daidadada Tenshi", 10 million views is soon? Well, not quite yet.
ありがとうございます！これからもね、いっぱい歌ってみた動画ね、投稿していきたいと思っているので
Thank you! I want to keep posting lots of cover videos from now on,
え、よかったら楽しみにしててくださーい、お願いします！
so please look forward to it, I'd appreciate it!
そして、気が付いたらアクア城からタイムワープしちゃっている。ここはどこ？私は誰？
And before I knew it, I time-warped from Aqua Castle. Where is this? Who am I?
えー、ホロリーナに、アクア城のセットが、なんか、いっぱいある！見て！
Uh, in Hololina, there's lots of Aqua Castle sets! Look!
わ、すごい！わ、なんかアクア仕様の、すごいうわすごいすごい！
Wow, amazing! Wow, like Aqua-themed, wow amazing amazing!
わ、すごいよ！新色してるめっちゃ、めっちゃ、すごい！やばいやばい！
Wow, it's amazing! Coloring is super, super, amazing! No way!
猫とかいんだけど！見て、猫がすごい、両方に猫が、なんか、守り神みたいになってない？
There are cats! Look, the cats are amazing, cats on both sides, aren't they like guardian deities?
なんとね、あとね、えっとね、アクア風船もね、こっち側にも、こっちもね、こっちもね、いっぱいあるの！
And amazingly, also, um, Aqua balloons are here too, on this side, that side, everywhere!
すごい！浮いてる！
Amazing! They're floating!
かわいい！いいね！
Cute! Nice!
なんかどんどんアクア色に染まっちゃっている気がする。
I feel like I'm getting dyed more and more in Aqua color.
いやもっとね、やっぱね、このステージもね、みんなもね、アクア色に染まってほしいなって思ってます！
And even more, I hope everyone and this stage too will get dyed in Aqua color!
ということで、続いてはオリジナル曲を歌いたいと思います！
With that said, next up I'd like to sing an original song!
それでは盛り上がっていきましょう！フォー・ザ・ウィン！
Let's get hyped up! For The Win!
For the win ビンビンビン For the win ビンビンビン 信じててね、大丈夫、アクア色に染めるよ、君と歩くこの未来を
For the win, believe in me, it'll be alright, I'll dye you in Aqua color, this future we walk together!
For the win! win! win!
自分らしさはどこだろう
Where is my true self?
自分なりに探しても
Even if I search in my own way,
うまくいかないことだらけよ
it's full of things that don't go well.
仕方ないなあ 空回りしちゃって
Can't be helped, spinning my wheels,
失敗して笑われたって
failing and being laughed at,
頑張って 頑張って ここにいる
I worked hard, worked hard, and I'm here.
キミも同じだよ 諦めなきゃきっと
You're the same too, if you don't give up, surely
つかめるから
you can grasp it.
For the win! win! win!
夢を叫ぶんだ 今 ここで
Shouting out my dream, right here, right now,
叶えたいものは何？ ひとつ教えてよ
what is the dream you want to fulfill? Tell me one.
For the win! win! win!
信じるだけ できるでしょ？
Just believing is something you can do, right?
走り切った その先は
Beyond the finish line,
あくあ色の未来よ
is an Aqua-colored future.
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
いくよ Let's go! Fight, win!
Here we go! Let's go! Fight, win!
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
Yes! Aqua for the win!
伝えるのは下手だから
I'm bad at conveying my feelings,
誤解しないで聞いてよね
so don't misunderstand and listen to me.
私なりの応援だから 分かるでしょ？
It's my own way of cheering you on, so you understand, right?
ねぇ 笑ったって泣いたって一度きりって
Hey, whether laughing or crying, it's just once,
頑張って 頑張って ここに来た
I worked hard, worked hard, and came here.
キミがいないと 絶対たどり着けなかった場所だから
Because without you, I could never have reached this place.
For the win! win! win!
今度はぎゅっと私から キミの背中を押すよ
This time, I'll tightly push your back from my side,
強く優しくね
strongly and gently.
For the win! win! win!
前を向いて さあ行こう
Facing forward, let's go now,
見たことのない世界
to a world we've never seen before,
一緒に旅しようよ
let's travel together.
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
いくよ Let's go! Fight, win!
Here we go! Let's go! Fight, win!
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
Yes! Aqua for the win!
負けたくない くやしい涙があふれた日ですらも
Even the days when frustrated, tearful tears overflowed,
無駄じゃない 私らしさを作っていく
aren't wasted, they shape who I am.
だから 大丈夫 大丈夫 心配ないよ
So it's alright, it's alright, don't worry.
大丈夫 大丈夫 全力で走り続けたんだ
It's alright, it's alright, I kept running with all my might.
キミならできるさ
You can do it!
喜びも悲しみも分かち合えるひとがいる
Having someone to share joys and sorrows with,
初めて気づいたんだ ひとりじゃないんだって
I realized for the first time that I'm not alone.
For the win! win! win!
仲間たちと叶えたい 夢はきっとこの場所で
The dream I want to fulfill with my comrades is surely in this place,
あくあ色に輝く
shining in Aqua color.
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
いくよ Let's go! Fight, win!
Here we go! Let's go! Fight, win!
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
Yes! Aqua for the win!
みんな！たずね来てくれて、どうもありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you so much for coming to visit!
いっぱい盛り上がってね！最後まで絶対にコメント切れさないでね！
Get super hyped! Make sure your comments don't cut out until the very end!
よかったら「A・Q・U・A」のところコメントで「A・Q・U・Aあくあしか勝たん」って言ってね！
If you'd like, when it's 'A-Q-U-A', comment 'A-Q-U-A Aqua is the best!'
負けたくない くやしい涙があふれた日ですらも
Even the days when frustrated, tearful tears overflowed,
無駄じゃない 私らしさを作っていく
aren't wasted, they shape who I am.
だから 大丈夫 大丈夫 心配ないよ
So it's alright, it's alright, don't worry.
大丈夫 大丈夫 全力で走り続けたんだ
It's alright, it's alright, I kept running with all my might.
キミならできるさ
You can do it!
喜びも悲しみも分かち合えるひとがいる
Having someone to share joys and sorrows with,
初めて気づいたんだ ひとりじゃないんだって
I realized for the first time that I'm not alone.
For the win! win! win!
仲間たちと叶えたい 夢はきっとこの場所で
The dream I want to fulfill with my comrades is surely in this place,
あくあ色に輝く
shining in Aqua color.
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
いくよ Let's go! Fight, win!
Here we go! Let's go! Fight, win!
A・Q・U・A
A-Q-U-A
Yes! Aqua for the win!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
はい、ということで、えー、For the win でした！ありがとう！
Right, so, that was 'For The Win'! Thank you!
ということでですね、次はなんと、ゲストが、私のこの3Dライブにゲストが来てくれるんですが、
And so, next, amazingly, a guest... a guest is coming to my 3D live, but,
その前に、ここからはちょっと、ちょっとだけ、告知タイムもさせていただきたいと思います！
before that, from here I'd like to do just a little, a little bit of an announcement time!
いやね、ちょっとね、あの、ちょっとだけ紹介させてほしい、いい？でもさ、やっぱ今回3周年だからさ、ちょっとお願い、紹介させて、お願い！いい？
Well, you know, I want to introduce it just a little bit, is that okay? But you know, since it's the 3rd anniversary, please let me introduce it, please! Okay?
いい？ごめんね？いい？ということで、じゃあ、えー、告知させていただきたいと思います。こちら、どどーん！
Okay? Sorry? Okay? So, well, I'd like to make an announcement. Here it is, ta-da!
みなとあくあ活動三周年記念グッズ、イエーイ！
Minato Aqua 3rd anniversary commemorative goods, yay!
さんに、の、え、直筆サインポストカード付きって書いてある。
It says it comes with a hand-signed postcard.
直筆サイン書きます！よろしくお願いします。
I'll write a handwritten signature! Thank you very much.
じゃあね、ちょっと詳しく説明していくと、みなとあくあ 3rd Anniversaryの
So, to explain in more detail, Minato Aqua's 3rd Anniversary
複製原画というのが、なんとですね、今回、出させていただくことになりまして、
reproduction art will be released this time!
え、原画を描いてくださっているのは、えっと、トモセシンスケ先生です！
The original art was drawn by Tomose Shunsuke-sensei!
トモセシンスケ先生といえばね、やっぱり、普段の仕事でもお世話になったりしてね、
Speaking of Tomose Shunsuke-sensei, I've actually worked with him on regular projects,
今回はなんとね、え、3周年のね、え、ライブのキービジュアルをね、描いてくださったということで、本当にありがとうございます！
and this time, he drew the key visual for my 3rd anniversary live! Thank you so much!
いやね、すっごい豪華な感じになってるので、ぜひみんなね、買ってください。
It's super gorgeous, so everyone, please be sure to buy it.
そして、それ以外にも、え、あくキャットTシャツということで、え、どっとTシャツだ！あくキャットどっとTシャツということで、
And besides that, for the Aqua Cat T-shirts... wait, Dot T-shirts! Aqua Cat Dot T-shirts,
え、にゃにゃにゃにゃって、ありました。あくキャットの動画がですね、の、
there's... um, Nyan nyan nyan! There's an Aqua Cat video, right?
えっと、イラストがあったよね、私が猫に乗ってさ、宇宙を飛んでいるやつ。あれが、え、どっとTシャツになって、
There was an illustration of me riding a cat flying through space, right? That has become a dot T-shirt
え、発売されることになりました！めっちゃかわいいから、まじで！すっごいかわいいから、まじでね、みんなね、チェックしてください。
and is going to be released! It's super cute, seriously! It's so cute, seriously, everyone check it out.
毎日ね、あの、そのどっとTシャツで、あの、外に歩いてください。うん、めちゃ注目されると思うから。うん。
Wear that dot T-shirt and walk outside every day. Yeah, you'll definitely get a lot of attention. Yeah.
そして、え、あくキャットのキーホルダーも発売されます！いぇーい！
And also, Aqua Cat keyholders will be released! Yay!
だからね、キーホルダー100個くらい買って、みんなね、あの、いたバッグ作ってくれると嬉しいです。でね、にゃにゃにゃにゃって、みんなでね、あの、更新しましょう。うん。
So I'd be happy if you bought about 100 keyholders and made an itaba bag! And let's update it together like 'Nyan nyan nyan!', yeah.
そして、なんとですね、私恥ずかしがりだからあんまりね、あの、ボイスとか出さないんですけども、まね、あの、みんながね、本当に、もう早く出してよって、いつ出すのあくたんってずっと言われておりまして、
And you know, I'm kind of shy so I don't usually release voice packs, but everyone kept saying 'Hurry up and release it!' and 'When is Aktan releasing it?',
はい、3周年ということで、ボイスを、え、出させていただくことになりました！ちょっとマジで話、恥ずかしいから聞かないでください。
so yes, for our 3rd anniversary, I'm finally releasing a voice pack! Seriously, it's so embarrassing, please don't listen to it.
聞かないで、これだけはかわいくなくていいです、みんなさん。はい。
Don't listen to it, you don't have to find this part cute, everyone. Yes.
そして、フルセットご予約の方には、え、枚数限定で、え、みなとあくあ直筆サイン入りポストカードがついてきまーす！いぇーい！
And for those who pre-order the full set, a limited-quantity hand-signed postcard by Minato Aqua will be included! Yay!
いやね、ずっとね、配信でやりたいやりたいって言ってたんだけど、なかなかね、忙しかったりして、ちょっと実現できなかったので、ま、この機会にね、いや、ちょっとやりたいと思います！いっぱいね、サイン書いちゃいますので、よろしくお願いいたします！
I've been saying in streams for a long time that I wanted to do this, but I was so busy I couldn't make it happen, so I'd love to take this opportunity! I'll be signing a lot of them, so please look forward to it!
そして、なんともう一個告知があります！告知2つ目！
And there is another announcement! Announcement number two!
みなとあくあビッグぬいぐるみが、なんと、復活しました！いぇーい！
Minato Aqua's Big Plushie has somehow made a comeback! Yay!
ということでね、去年、えっと、夏のね、私の、え、ソロワンマンライブで、え、発売されて好評だったみなとあくあビッグぬいぐるみが、再販されることになりました！いぇーい！
So, the Minato Aqua Big Plushie that was released and became popular at my solo one-man live last summer will be re-released! Yay!
いやね、あの5月に、今年の5月にね、猫ぬいぐるみが出て、で、あの、あ、あくあぬいぐるみないのかな、とか、あ、あくあぬいぐるみあったんだけど、もう売ってないんだ、みたいな声がすごくあって、
You know, back in May, this year's May, cat plushies came out, and people were saying 'Is there no Aqua plushie?' or 'There was one, but they don't sell it anymore?',
そう、まね、去年ね、私のことまだ知らなかった、知らなかったって人にも、え、届けられるようにご用意しました！めっちゃかむじゃん今日。めっちゃ噛むんだけど今日。
so, to make sure even those who didn't know me yet last year could get one, we prepared this! Man, I'm stumbling on my words so much today. I'm stumbling so much today.
ということでね、これがもしかしたら最後のチャンスになるかもしれないので、よかったらお見逃しなく！
So, this might be your last chance, so please don't miss out!
みんなね、いっぱいね、抱きしめてください。ビッグぬいぐるみをぎゅって、あのね、あの、殴ったりしちゃダメです、やめてくださいね。ぎゅって、あの、大切にしてください。
Everyone, hug it a lot. Give the big plushie a big squeeze... hey, don't punch it or anything, please don't do that. Give it a gentle squeeze and cherish it.
ということで、よろしいか、大丈夫だね。あの、ちょっとも噛んでないね。オッケーオッケーオッケー。詳しい詳細は概要欄を見てもらったり、あとでねTwitterなどでもお知らせするので、チェックしてください！お願いします！
Alright, is that everything? We're good, right? I didn't stumble at all. Okay, okay, okay. Check the video description for full details, and I'll also post updates on Twitter later, so please check it out! Thank you!
ということで、ここで、ゲストをお呼びしちゃいます！いぇーい！
And with that, we're going to invite our guest right here! Yay!
ということでね、誰だろうね、ゲスト。まね、私の3D配信のゲストになんと初めて、なんですけれども、ライブロットね、初めてなんですけれども、
So, who could the guest be? You know, this is actually the very first guest for my 3D stream... well, for a live performance it's a first, but,
やっぱり初めてのゲストはこの人かなって思ってます。ということでね、
I figured the very first guest should be this person. So,
それでは、え、私の運命の赤い糸でつながっているお相手、それでは、え、呼びます。
now then, let's call my partner connected by the red string of fate.
ねこっちゃん、お帰り！
Neko-chan, welcome back!
え？
"Eh?"
あれ？
"Huh?"
あれ？あれ？
"Huh? Huh?"
はい、どーも！
"Hi, hello!"
もぐもぐおかゆ！
"Mogu-mogu Okayu!"
猫又おかゆです。
"I'm Nekomata Okayu."
おかゆ、ありがとう来てくれて！
"Okayu, thanks for coming!"
ちょきっ
"Choki—"
ちょきちょきちょき…ちょきちょきちょきじゃないよ！きっちゃったよ！
"Choki-choki-choki... Wait, choki-choki-choki? No, you cut it!"
切っちゃったー！
"You cut it!"
もう切っちゃったよー
"You already cut it!"
こんなに３年も長くためとこ、この赤い糸が、あ、あ
"I saved this red string for three whole years, ah, ah..."
まあ、リサイクルして誰かに使ってもらおう！
"Well, let's recycle it and let someone else use it!"
なんてだよ！誰だよ！運命なんだからこれ！
"What do you mean! Who! This is destiny!"
あくあならたくさんいるよ、いい人は。
"Aqua, there are plenty of good guys out there."
なんでだよ！また適当言って！おかゆが来てくれました！
"Why! Saying random things again! Okayu came for us!"
あー、どうもどうも！久しぶりじゃんめっっちゃ。
"Ah, hello hello! It's been so long."
一緒に放送するのは、あの、めっっちゃ…めちゃ久しぶりだよね、おか…おか…おかゆぶりじゃない？
"Broadcasting together is... wow, it's been a super long time, Okayu, right?"
あ、頭が、え？頭、お、お、おかゆ、おかゆ、おにぎり…あ、頭が、頭が…
"Ah, my head... Eh? My head, O-O-Okayu, Okayu, onigiri... Ah, my head, my head..."
まあまあまあまあ、今日はでもおかゆじゃないからね！
"Well, well, well, well, today isn't Okayu, though!"
猫またおかゆ、おかゆだからね！そうだよね！なんとね、おかゆはね、
"Nekomata Okayu, it's Okayu! That's right! You see, Okayu..."
今日このね、３周年配信のために、レッスンをね、ダンスレッスンを、そう、してくれたんだよ！
"For today's 3rd anniversary stream, she took lessons, dance lessons, for us!"
もう僕普段はね、え、ダンスわかんない、踊れないって感じなんだけどさ、
"Normally I'm like, 'Eh, I don't know dance, I can't dance,' but..."
今日はでもね、あくあのね、ちょっと切っちゃったけど大事な３周年だったんで、頑張ってダンスを練習しました！
"Today, though, since it was Aqua's important 3rd anniversary even though I cut it, I worked hard and practiced dancing!"
おかゆ、私のために苦手なダンスレッスンを？そうだよ！
"Okayu, dance lessons even though you're bad at it for my sake? That's right!"
頑張ったんだから！３周年のためにわざわざ来てくれて、そして歌も覚えてダンスも覚えて、そんな過酷なことを？
"I worked hard for it! Coming all the way for the 3rd anniversary, memorizing songs and dances, such a harsh thing?"
そうだよ！過酷だったよ！おかゆってば、それってもう！
"That's right! It was harsh! Okayu, that means..."
私のこと好きすぎ！好きすぎ！好きすぎ！
"You love me too much! Too much! Too much!"
ほんでっちゃったけど大丈夫！
"It flew off, but I'm fine!"
もう疲れないけど！
"I'm not tired anymore!"
ちょっと…危ない危ない危ない！
"Wait... Dangerous, dangerous, dangerous!"
帰ってきた帰ってきた！危ない危ない危ない危ない！
"It came back! Dangerous, dangerous, dangerous, dangerous!"
何その…飛んでいっちゃったじゃん！使うから今年！2021年の、あ、私のこと好きすぎ！
"What is that... it flew away! I'll use it this year! 2021's... Ah, you love me too much!"
やっぱ形を変えていかないとね、どんどん。そう、あきらめちゃうから。
"After all, we have to change forms, or else we'll give up."
そうだね。あきらめちゃんもね、あかゆいとみたいにね、あきらめられてね。
"That's right. Akirame-chan too, like red thread, gets given up on."
いや、私には見えるんだけど。あれ、いや、そうだよ、それは！
"No, I can see it. Huh? No, that's right, that's..."
思い込みの狂気だよ、それは！思い込みの狂気、あ、頭が…
"That's the madness of delusion! The madness of delusion, ah, my head..."
え、でもね、今日はそんなね、ダンスをねずっとね頑張ってくれたおかゆに、プレゼントがあります！
"Eh, but today, for Okayu who worked hard on dancing like that, I have a present!"
プレゼント！？なになにどこどこ？みんなでちょっとお気づきかと思うんだけど、ここ！
"A present!? What, what, where, where? You guys might have noticed, but here!"
見て見て、耳んとこ！おー！
"Look, look, at the ears! Ooh!"
見て見て、おかゆの耳も見て！ぼくの耳？
"Look, look, look at Okayu's ears too! My ears?"
おにぎり付いてる！おにぎり付いてる！耳そこやん！耳そこやんけ！
"An onigiri is attached! An onigiri is attached! Your ear is right there! Your ear is right there!"
あれ？なんか…もぐもぐもぐもぐ…あ、お、なんか付いてる！
"Huh? Something... mogu-mogu-mogu... Oh, oh, something is attached!"
ちょっと…ちょっと見えづらいかもだけどさ、ポンポンが付いてる！
"Wait... It might be a bit hard to see, but pom-poms are attached!"
なんと、お揃いのイヤモニを…お揃いのね、とびっきり可愛い写真が撮れましたから！やったー！
"What's more, matching in-ear monitors... We took a super cute matching picture! Yay!"
お揃っちだよこれ！どう？お揃っちだ！
"It's matching! How's that? It's matching!"
どう見えないけど…見えないし！
"How? I can't see it... and I can't see it either!"
僕は耳がここだから聞こえないけど、でも嬉しい！
"My ears are here so I can't hear it, but I'm happy!"
あれ、発注ミスったかな、これ？ちょっとここだよ！あれ？でも、ここにあるとね、こう、すごい長いことになっちゃうからね。
"Huh, did I mess up the order? Wait, it's right here! Huh? But if it's here, it'll be super long."
まあ確かにね。ちょっと長くね。
"Well, that's true. A bit long."
でも、ありがとう！嬉しい！え、すごい似合ってるよ！可愛い！
"But thank you! I'm happy! Eh, it suits you so well! Cute!"
嬉しい、ありがとう！可愛いねんな。
"I'm happy, thank you! So cute."
ではね、うん、プレゼントもね、したことだし、ダンスも頑張ってくれたし、やっぱね、あの曲をね、一緒に歌おうよ！
"Well then, yeah, since I gave a present, and you worked hard on dancing, let's sing that song together!"
あの曲？そうそう！
"That song? Yeah, yeah!"
なんの曲を歌って踊るんだっけ？
"What song was it we sing and dance to again?"
あの曲だよ、あの曲！「愛のラブソング」私たちの…え？
"That song, that song! 'Love Song of Love,' our... Eh?"
教えてもらってもいい？
"Could you teach me?"
仕方ないなあおかゆ。こっち来て。うん。
"Can't be helped, Okayu. Come here. Yeah."
なんだろ。それでは皆さま、お待たせいたしました！私と猫又おかゆによる、ぬるるるる…おかゆによるね、大事をと、感じちゃった。
"I wonder what. Well then everyone, thank you for waiting! Presented by me and Nekomata Okayu, nururururu... By Okayu, it felt important."
大丈夫、大丈夫！はい、せーの！
"It's fine, it's fine! Yes, ready, go!"
私と猫又おかゆによる、愛のラブソング、聞いてください。
"Please listen to 'Love's Love Song' by me and Nekomata Okayu."
チューリングラブ！
"Turing Love!"
あぁ、恋の定義がわからない
"Ah, I don't know the definition of love"
まずスキって基準もわからない
"First of all, I don't even know the criteria for liking someone"
あー、恋の定義がわからない
Oh, I don't know the definition of love
まずスキって基準もわからない
First of all, I don't know the standard
要は、恋してるときが恋しい
In short, I'm in love when I'm in love
客観? 主観?
Objective? Subjective?
エビデンスプリーズ!
Evidence please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love cannot be solved by calculation
まず普通の計算も解けない
First, I can't even solve normal math
要はそんな状態が愛らしい
In short, that state is adorable
もう大抵の事象において Q があって A を出して解けるのに
Most of the time, almost every event has Q and you can solve it with A
勘違いって間違って 解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
What is this feeling without solution from misunderstandings?
(検証 is 不明瞭)
(Verification is unclear)
ダーリング モーションは相対性にステイ
Dazing!! Motion stays in relativity
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love - Mellow that can't be solved even if you stare
ワットイズラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What is Love - Now 123, shall we prove it?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
Questions created with words
ハートで高鳴るアンサー
Answer that roars with a heart
測ったって不確定性 僕らの BPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love - Even if you fly in the air, I don't believe it
フォーリングラブ いまは ABC すらバグりそうだ
Foreign Love - Now even ABC seems to be buggy
なんでか教えてオイラー
Tell me why, Euler
感想聞かせてフェルマー
Tell me your impressions, Fermat
予測不可能性 いま触れてみる
Let's touch on the unpredictability
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
間違いのないように
So that there's no mistake
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情全部全部
All these emotions
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるなら
If there's a correct answer
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
シンプルな Q.E.D.
Simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい!
I want to prove it today!
目に見えない無理難題を
Invisible, impossible tasks
ASAP!
導き出したい 辿り着きたい 最適解へ
I want to find and reach the optimal solution
何度からまったってぶつかっちゃったって
No matter how many times we got tangled or collided
不思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さえ必要条件です
Unraveling this mysterious anomaly is a necessary condition
三次元(立体)における2点AB間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between two points AB in 3D space
的な感じだと思ってたのに
I thought it was a typical problem, but
座標も公式も見当たらないし
Neither coordinates nor formulas are found
参考資料にも載ってないから君と生み出して見せたいじゃん
And it's not in references, so I want to create it with you
三次元(世界)におけるこの気持ちの求め方
How to find this feeling in 3D (the world)
丸だって バツだって 不安だって equal で
Circle, cross, anxiety, equal,
近くなって 遠くなって 揺れる、この気持ちのハリも
Getting closer, getting farther, the tension of this swaying feeling
(条件は明瞭)
(Condition is clear)
Steppin'!! モーションは相関性にステイ
Steppin'!! Motion stays in correlation
チューリングラブ さわぎだした胸の痛くなるほど
Turing Love - The chest starting to ache so much
証明たちはいまも角度を増しているようだ
The proofs seem to be increasing their angle even now
あいまいも除外して、最大の仮説を
Excluding ambiguity, the greatest hypothesis
いま、ふたりなら実証できそう
Now, the two of us can probably demonstrate it
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love - Mellow that can't be solved even if you stare
ワットイズラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What is Love - Now 123, shall we prove it?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン
Questions created with words
ハートで高鳴るアンサー
Answer that roars with a heart
測ったって不確定性 僕らの BPM
Uncertainty measured by our BPM
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love - Even if you fly in the air, its causality too
フォーリングラブ いまは XYZ までわかりそうだ
Foreign Love - Now I can understand up to XYZ
確かめさせてピタゴラス
Let me confirm, Pythagoras
確かめさせてリーマン
Let me be sure, Riemann
予測ずみ可変性 いま触れてみる
Let's touch on the predictable variability
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
間違いのないように
So that there's no mistake
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情全部全部
All these emotions
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるなら
If there's a correct answer
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
推測を超えて!
Beyond guesswork!
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
間違いのないように
So that there's no mistake
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
この感情全部全部
All these emotions
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
正解があるなら
If there's a correct answer
さあ証明しよう
Let's prove it
シンプルな Q.E.D.
Simple Q.E.D.
おかゆー！
Okayu!
私たちってば夫婦になっちゃったんだけど！
We ended up becoming a married couple!
え、どうしようね？
Eh, what should we do?
え、ちょっと待って！待って待って！待ってちょっと、ええーっ！？嘘、言っちゃったんですけど！
Eh, wait! Wait, wait! Wait a second, ehh?! No way, I actually said it!
え？
Eh?
おかゆ... いや、おかいゅさんでした！
Okayu... Ah, I mean Okayu-san!
ありがとうございました！またコラボをしましょうね！
Thank you very much! Let's collab again!
え、おかゆとあれれ、あれれれれれれ...
Eh, Okayu and... huh, huh, huh...
あれれれれれれ...
Huh, huh, huh...
しばらくお待ちください
[Please wait for a moment]
ということで、おかゆとのチューリングラブどうだったかなみんな！ありがとね！
So, how was the Turing Love duet with Okayu, everyone? Thank you!
いやマジで、ちょっとさ、二人で一緒に踊るってさ、すごいなんかちょっとさ、なんか、何？愛の共同作業みたいでちょっとなんかドキドキしちゃったんだけど、みんなどうだったかな？ありがとうございした！
Seriously, dancing together like that felt kind of like a collaborative labor of love, and my heart was pounding a bit. How did you guys find it? Thank you!
からみんなともっとね、えー、あくあ色。
...so that everyone and I can share even more Aqua color together.
みんなとあくあのあくあで、えー、ピンクと青で、えー、色々、なんか、すべて
Combining Aqua's Aqua, pink, blue, and everything else into Aqua color...
含めて、あくあ色でね、えー、いっぱいね、みんなもね、楽しく、そして、そのあくあ色の輪をもっと広げていけたらいいなって思っておりますので、今後とも
I hope to expand this circle of Aqua color even further, so I look forward to your continued support...
どうぞよろしくお願いします。お願いします。
Thank you all very much. Thank you!
まだね、すごーく未熟な私けれども、もっと強くなってね、みんなに、こう、自分の成長していく姿を、見せていけたらいいなって思ってるから、これからも応援よろしくお願いします。
I'm still very inexperienced, but I hope to grow stronger and show you all my growth.
3周年ほんとにありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for the 3rd anniversary.
ということで、最後の歌を歌わせていただきたいと思います。
And with that, I'd like to sing my final song.
最後はですね、えー、新曲をみんなに聞いてもらいたいと思ってます。
For the very last one, I want everyone to listen to a brand new song.
えー、3周年の、えー、オリジナルの曲の新曲です。
It's a new original song for my 3rd anniversary.
えー、この曲は、私のだいすきな40mPさんに書き下ろしをしていただきました。
This song was written and composed especially for me by 40mP, whom I love so much.
すごいね、やっぱ3周年ということで、こう今までの景色とか、今見えている場所とか、こう、このライブがあって、そしてみんながいてくれて、私がいて、なんか、そういう、なんだろう、すごい、最初はすっごく寂しかったけど、今はこんなにたくさんの人がいて、こう、すごい、多くの人に祝っていただける3周年になったなって思ってて、そんなね、えー、4年目を迎えることができたのもみんなのおかげだと思っております。
You know, with it being the 3rd anniversary, I thought about the scenery until now, the places I see now, this live concert, everyone being here, and me being here. At first it was so lonely, but now with so many people here celebrating my 3rd anniversary and reaching the 4th year, I feel like it's all thanks to everyone.
これからもね、みんなとずっと一緒にいたいっていう、そんな私の気持ちが詰まっている1曲になっているので、よかったら最後まで聴いてください。
This song is packed with my feelings of wanting to stay together with everyone forever, so I hope you'll listen to it until the end.
それでは、えー、このあとね、えーと、プレミアム公開で、えー動画が投稿されると思うので、ライブの後もぜひチェックしてみてください！えー、素敵なね、すっごく手のこんだPVも、えー、あるので、よかったら最後まで聴いてくれると嬉しいです。
Well then, a video will be posted shortly as a premiere after this, so please be sure to check it out after the live! There's also a wonderful, elaborately crafted PV, so I'd be happy if you listened to it to the end.
ということで、最後の曲、聴いてください。
And with that, please listen to the final song.
海想列車
Oceanic Train
海想列車 作詞/作曲：40mP
[Title: Oceanic Train / Music & Lyrics: 40mP]
海想列車　頬を少しだけ　夢の中で
Oceanic Train, just brushing my cheek in a dream
ゆらゆら　揺られて　波に包まれていたい
Swaying, swaying, I want to be wrapped in the waves
夢を見てた　あの頃の夢を
I was dreaming, the dream from those days
臆病だった　どこにも行けなかった
I was timid, I couldn't go anywhere
変わりたくて　電車に乗り込んだ
Wanting to change, I boarded a train
この世界で一枚だけのきっぷ
With the only ticket in this world
路線図の時刻表も　今は白紙だけど
The route map and timetable are still blank, but...
窓の向こうには　青より青い水平線
Beyond the window lies a horizon bluer than blue
海想列車　頬を少しだけ　怖いけれど
Oceanic Train, just brushing my cheek, even though it's scary
走り出した夢は　もうとまらない
The dream that started running can no longer be stopped
世界なんて考えてみても　わからないから
Even if I try to think about the world, I won't understand, so
目の前に広がる　この景色を見ていたい
I want to look at this scenery spreading out before my eyes
夢を見てた　あの頃の夢を
I was dreaming, the dream from those days
ひとりじゃきっと　ここまでこれなかった
Alone, I surely couldn't have come this far
途中の駅で降りたその時も　君がいつのそばにいてくれた
Even when I got off at a station along the way, you were always by my side
ごめんねもありがとうも　まだ言い足りてないよ
I haven't said "I'm sorry" or "Thank you" enough yet
私のペースで　不器用なりに伝えてくから
I'll convey it clumsily, at my own pace
海場を走り抜け　まだ知らない…
Running across the sea, to places I don't know yet...
海想列車 夢から覚めた
Woke up from a dream on the imaginary train,
懐かしくて 変わらない想いをそっと抱きしめた
Gently embracing feelings so nostalgic and unchanging.
笑い合って 手を取り合って 同じ時間を過ごした
Laughing together, holding hands, spending time together,
君と これからもずっと
with you, forever from now on.
海想列車 もう怖くない 無我夢中で
Imaginary train, I'm no longer scared, running recklessly,
駆け抜けた日々は夢じゃないから
the days I ran through are no mere dream.
世界なんて考えてみてもわからないけど
Even if I try to think about the world, I won't understand, but
目の前に広がるこの景色を見ていたい
I want to keep looking at this scenery spreading before my eyes.
君と一緒にこの景色を見ていたい
I want to look at this scenery together with you.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
このあとメンバーシップでよかったら3D配信するので、見に来てね！
After this, I'll be doing a 3D stream on membership if you'd like, so come check it out!
後ほどお会いしましょー！
See you later!
ということでお疲れさまでした！4年目もよろしくね！
With that said, great job everyone! Here's to our 4th year as well!
見てくれてありがとう！4年目もよろしくね！
Thank you for watching! Here's to our 4th year too!